randstadusa.com 2019-05-17

# Privacy Policy | Randstad USA

Last updated: March 28, 2016

This is the Privacy Policy for the Randstad website maintained by Randstad General Partner (US) LLC on behalf of Randstad and its other subsidiaries, affiliates and divisions and their respective successors and assigns (collectively, as used in this Privacy Policy, "Randstad").

### overview

The primary purposes of the Randstad website are: 

  1. to provide employers who are existing or prospective clients of Randstad with an online tool and resources to post job openings and orders and with other relevant information; and  
  2. to provide professionals who are seeking jobs with an online tool and resources to assess and evaluate available opportunities that may match their qualifications and preferences and to submit their resumes and other relevant information to apply for such positions.

As a result of its purposes, use of this website facilitates and inherently involves the collection and exchange of valuable and sensitive information among employers, job seekers and Randstad. This Privacy Policy covers the collection, use, sharing, retention, care and disposal of personal information by or on behalf of Randstad of or relating to:    

  1. anonymous visitors to the Randstad website, 
  2. persons who register as employers on the Randstad website,  
  3. persons who register as job seekers on the Randstad website, and  
  4. other individuals who may supply personal information to Randstad from time to time.   

By using this website, such persons expressly consent to this Privacy Policy.   
This Privacy Policy applies only to the Randstad website. Websites or online services provided by third parties accessible by a link on the Randstad website and users of this website who enter into any online communication or transaction with each other, such as a job seeker and employer, may have their own distinct privacy policy. Users assume responsibility for informing themselves of the privacy policies of such third parties and other users and making any user choices, including refraining from communicating with such third parties or other users whose privacy policy they do not accept. 

Randstad reserves the right to update this Privacy Policy from time to time. Any changes will only be effective prospectively, from the time such changes are published on the website and, with respect to any particular information of or relating to any person, Randstad will comply with this Privacy Policy as in effect at the time such information was supplied or obtained unless it obtains consent for the application of any other or different terms to such information.

### information collection

Randstad collects information from and regarding individuals in a variety of ways from a variety of sources. Randstad initially collects information from users of its website during their visits to the website. We may also collect information externally from this website, such as information regarding those job seekers who secure employment with or through Randstad and those employers who are or become clients of Randstad. This information enables us to profile the interests of employers and job seekers, post and solicit applications for job openings and orders and track the status of pending openings.

We sometimes afford job seekers and employers an opportunity to provide us with specific additional information when they enroll on this website and complete their profile, such as their physical geographical location. Providing this information is optional. However, providing this information helps us better serve job seekers, employers and other website visitors by including their preferences and choices on various options.

Randstad also collects and uses information by installing small computer files (known as cookies) on the hard drive of each computer used to visit our website. A cookie is a string of information sent by a website and stored on your hard drive or temporarily in your computer's memory. Cookies are an important element of your experience on our website. They allow us to welcome you each time you visit and customize our information to your past website experiences. Cookies also help us detect and stop fraud. 

The website may include first-party cookies (i.e., cookies that send data directly to Randstad and agents and contractors acting on behalf of Randstad, used to monitor, analyze and administer the website) and third-party cookies (i.e., cookies that send data to our contractors for their commercial use). The cookies on our website may also track Internet activities across different websites.

Some computer browsers permit you to disable or uninstall cookies, and you may do so by following the instructions provided by your hardware and software vendors. Randstad does not provide the means for you to opt out of having cookies placed on your computer, and makes no representation or warranty that the disabling devices provided by your hardware and software vendors will be effective to block or remove the cookies. However, disabling or uninstalling these cookies will adversely impact the user experience on the Randstad website and may prevent you from accessing and using certain features of the website.

Randstad and the vendor hosting this website collect traffic data regarding this 

website

, and such data collection activities may involve interaction with cookies, the collection of user IP addresses and the exchange of numeric codes used to identify a computer. Your computer's IP address is not necessarily linked to your personally identifiable 

information,

but does distinguish your computer from other computers that access the Randstad website. Randstad may use traffic data and your computer's IP address to help diagnose problems with its server, analyze trends, administer its website, serve more relevant advertising via Google's advertising network and for other purposes. Randstad may also use your computer's IP address to identify you as a distinct, though anonymous, visitor, for whom the experience may be personalized during future visits.

To opt out of the Google remarketing advertising network, visit [Google's Ad Preference Manager](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/?hl=en&sig=ACi0TCivrxzhIQFNwWltJOQkVfUSyI5nxidmBBpuljxngspKIXSxRVtoTUMUbxCYPHBFciF99cenY84rfy4uVVLLgVAvb8AJ6lHIrVxJIGQyzaXgj_22qzkZKwI78XIgYXMvIvrygkIb042taH7RuwxfAUbqvm0G_15vv2VowjDHOySv4oC1pwpGNFRBfxUxKN8el44sBMV3).

### tracking

Some Web browsers may be configured to send Do Not Track signals to websites, or users may use similar mechanisms to indicate a user’s preference that certain web technologies not be used to track the user’s online activity. The website does not accept or process such Do Not Track signals or similar mechanisms.

### information use

Randstad uses each registered job seeker's personal information to administer the various services opted for by the job seeker and to make the job seeker aware of career opportunities and other developments from time to time. Personal data is information which can be used to identify you, such as name, date of birth, identification number or other factors specific to your 

identity

, such as address, telephone, email or cell/mobile number. 

The user information that Randstad collects may be added to our databases and used for business purposes, including for marketing and promotional purposes, for a statistical analysis of users’ behavior, for product development, for content improvement, or to customize the content and layout of the website. In addition, Randstad will, on occasion, send emails to you about job information you requested from the website or third-party products. If you do not want to receive 

email

from us, visit the “

Opt Out

” or “Unsubscribe” link at the bottom of any Randstad email to remove yourself from continued receipt of such email messages.  

Among other uses, Randstad uses the information to identify an individual as a registered job seeker, to present potential employment opportunities to the job seeker, to present the job seeker to potential employers and to report these transactions to the relevant job seeker. We also give each job seeker the option to receive certain targeted communications from time to time.

### information sharing

With the job seeker's permission, Randstad may submit the job seeker's resume, application and/or other information to a prospective employer on the basis that such prospective employer will not disclose the fact that such job seeker is seeking employment or communicate with any other person regarding the contents of such job seeker's resume or application except with the job seeker's consent or otherwise in compliance with applicable labor and employment laws.

Randstad may also from time to time submit the job seeker's profile, with sufficient information removed so that the job seeker is not readily personally identifiable, to prospective employers to solicit their potential interest in him or her as a job candidate. 

Randstad may share a job seeker's personal information with entities with whom it contracts to assist in administering the website, including the job board on the website, from time to time. We may also share user information with third party companies and individuals with whom we contract in connection with the following: to facilitate the website; to provide the website or portions of the website on our behalf; to perform related services, including without limitation, maintenance services, database management, fulfillment, web analytics and improvement of the features or functionality of the website. 

Randstad may also share a job seeker's personal information with business partners to offer you goods, services and other incentives relating to the website and the job board. Once we establish and maintain an employment, staffing or placement relationship with you, we use the data you provided to us to comply with laws and regulations, including but not limited to employment law, tax and social security and national and international sanctions regulation compliance. For the purposes mentioned above, Randstad may transfer your personal data to other Randstad entities that provide services on behalf of Randstad. 

We may also share your information with any successor or assign some or all of the relevant part of our business, whether through a sale of our business, merger or otherwise.

We may share user information with appropriate third parties when we believe, in our sole discretion, that such sharing is appropriate: to comply with the law, including but not limited to, in response to a subpoena served on Randstad; to enforce or apply this Privacy Policy or other applicable terms, rules or policies; to protect the rights, property or safety of Randstad, our users or others; or to prevent activity that we believe, in our sole discretion, may be or may become illegal, unethical or legally actionable (including exchanging user information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection).

In all cases in which we share a job seeker's personal information, we will seek contractual commitments from the party with whom we share such information to abide by the same terms and conditions as those applicable to us in this Privacy Policy regarding the use, sharing, retention, care and disposal of such information.  

Please note that if you use any bulletin board, chat room, comment posting feature or 

other public communication service

, forum or feature offered through the website, or post any information available for viewing by other users, any of the information that you share will be visible to other users. The information that you make available can be read, used and collected by other users to send you unsolicited messages outside of the website. Randstad is not responsible for the manner in which any information that you decide to share by such public communication services will be used by other users.

We may release aggregate user information (without revealing any personal information) to advertisers and other third parties in order to promote or describe use of the website. 

### information security

Randstad restricts access to the personal information it collects to those who have a valid business need to know that information. Access to personal information is granted based on the minimum access required to fulfill the business need and purpose for which it is collected, used and shared. We endeavor to use commercially reasonable security safeguards, practices and procedures, and we commit to the highest level of care to protect the privacy and integrity of personal information, throughout its useful life-cycle, from collection until destruction.  

### information security incident response

If an unforeseen event occurs that results in the discovery that your personal information has been involved in a cyber-security or data breach incident, we will take appropriate steps to respond to the incident, in a timely manner and, if applicable, notify you of the incident so you can take whatever steps may be necessary to protect your personal information.  

### retention of personal information

Randstad will keep your personal information for as long as we have a business need and purpose to retain the information, including storage for auditing and archival purposes. When we believe we no longer need such information, we will destroy or otherwise dispose of your personal information in a manner intended to preserve your privacy and security.

### accessing and updating your profile

Job seekers may review, update or remove their job seeker profile directly from the website from time to time (subject to Randstad’s storage policies, as described above). You may also contact us and ask to see your job seeker profile and choices, and you may advise us of any changes or inaccuracies in such profile and choices and we will update or correct as appropriate.

### consultant texting applicants & employees

We are pleased to offer you the ability to opt-in to receive text messages from your Randstad Branch. If you elect to enroll to receive text messages from your Randstad Consultant, you will receive easy-to-check text messages related to Randstad. This information may include, but is not limited to, information such as job postings, assignment updates, weather alerts and reminders for upcoming events and services. Please see a Randstad Consultant to learn how to enroll.

### consultant texting opt-out

If at any time you wish to stop receiving text messages, you will have the option to opt-out by simply texting STOP after receiving a text from Randstad or you can contact Randstad and request to have your number removed through Randstad’s Call Center at 877.601.7453.

### international data transfer

By accessing and using the website, you acknowledge and agree that Randstad controls and operates all parts of the website from its offices in the United States of America and that the website is intended for use by users located in the United States of America. Unless expressly stated to the contrary, Randstad makes no representation that the website is appropriate or will be available for use in other countries. If you access the website from outside the United States, you acknowledge and agree that your information may be transferred to and maintained on computers and servers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may be different from those in your jurisdiction. Your consent to this Privacy Policy and other applicable terms, rules or policies followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to the transfer of such information to the United States and the collection, use and potential disclosure of your information in accordance with United States law and our Privacy Policy. 

### children's privacy

By using the website, you represent and warrant that you are thirteen (13) years of age or older and that you agree to and agree to abide by all applicable terms, rules and policies. Any access to or use of the website by anyone under the age of thirteen (13) is unauthorized. If Randstad believes that you are under the age of thirteen (13) or that you are not old enough to consent to and be legally bound by applicable terms, rules or policies, Randstad may, at any time, in its sole discretion, and with or without notice: (i) terminate your access to or use of the website (or any portion, aspect or feature of them), or (ii) delete any content or information that you have posted through the website.

### reporting fraudulent activities

If you become aware of any potentially fraudulent activity on our website or in an email or text, please contact Randstad's Call Center at 877.601.7453 so that we can follow up with appropriate actions. We take these matters and the protection of our applicants/employees sensitive information, very seriously.

### contacting randstad

If you have any questions, comments or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please [contact us](mailto:rus-informationsecurity-dl@randstadusa.com)[.](mailto:rus-informationsecurity-dl@randstadusa.com)
